



About

Hi! My name is Inês (Portuguese pronunciation: i'neʃ). I'm 28 years old and live in London, UK. I moved here in early 2019 for work.

I have a bachelor in Informatics Engineering by the University of Coimbra and have been working as a software developer for a few years now.

My hobbies include reading and playing Minecraft. I also enjoy listening to the occasional podcast (Soft Skills Engineering and No Such Thing As A Fish being my favorites at the moment). At the end of 2020 I decided to add learning French and React to the list - my website is a result of the latter.

I'm always looking for interesting opportunities, so feel free to say hi!

Education

Bachelor's Degree, Informatics Engineering at the University of Coimbra

O Sep 2012 to Aug 2017

• Coimbra, Portugal

Experience

Product Lead for Ethics Monitor at Haplo

O May 2019 to January 2021

• London, United Kingdom

Product lead for Ethics Monitor, which helps universities streamline the review of applications for ethical approval.

During my time at Haplo I worked closely with new clients throughout the process of building their custom application, provided support for existing clients and worked alongside my colleagues to improve the product.

Software Developer at HYP

O Sep 2018 to Jan 2019

• Coimbra, Portugal

Collaboration with The Loop Co to develop babyloop.pt, a platform to buy and sell used baby products (such as cribs, car seats, etc).

P GitLab

Ruby on Rails, Ruby, JavaScript

Junior Ruby Developer at OneSource

O Mar 2017 to Aug 2018

• Coimbra, Portugal

Extension for SketchUp to optimize the structure of the building designed by the user as well as maintenance and building costs so as to render the optimal solution. SketchUp's API was used to assess any relevant information of the building so as to conclude about properties like number of floors (including underground), available floor space, etc and therefore the costs and optimization needed.

GitHub وا

Ruby, JavaScript

Ruby on Rails Internship at HYP

O Jul 2016 to Sep 2016

• Coimbra, Portugal

Web application to pick movies to watch with friends, based on which movies everyone on the group wants to watch.

P GitLab

Ruby on Rails, Ruby, JavaScript

Skills

Programming

Javascript	★★★★☆	Redux	★★★☆☆
Ruby	★★★★☆	HTML/CSS	★★★☆☆
Ruby on Rails	★★★★☆	Java	★★★☆☆
React	★★★☆☆	Python	★★★☆☆
Git	★★★★☆		

Git	★★★★☆	ŕ	
Operating System Linux MacOS	is ★★★☆☆ ★★★☆☆	Windows	★★★☆ ☆
Languages Portuguese English	****	French	★★★☆☆

Contact

You can email me at ines.csim@gmail.com or call me on one of the following numbers: +44 7761 824051 (UK) / +351 935 889 881 (PT).

Looking forward to hearing from you.